무슨 일인데 그렇게
급하게 부른거야?
So, what's the big news you had us
rush all the way over here for?
길 건너는데 45분이나
걸렸으면서, 급하게 왔다고?
It took you 45 minutes
to cross a street.
아기 하나 가지고 뭘그래
Come on, guys. It's just one baby.
뭐야, 쟤네 편이야?
Oh, sure, now you guys clam up.
무슨 일이냐 하면..
회사에서 나더러 털사지점을 맡으래
Our news. My company has asked me
to head up our office in Tulsa.
그래서 월요일부터
그쪽으로 출근해야해
So as of Monday,
I'm being officially relocated.
- 세상에!
- 뭐라구? 월요일?
- Oh, my God!
- What? Monday?
- 얼마나 가있어야 하는데?
- 1년쯤 있어야 할걸
- How long do you have to go for?
- They said it could be up to a year.
- 뭐라구? 1년이나?
- 너도 가야해?
- A year?
- Well, do you have to go?
그래야 하지 않겠어?
Well, I kind of have to, don't I?
원수같은 이게 있잖니!
Because of this stupid thing.
사랑하는 아내의
내조만한건 없다니까
There's nothing like the support
of your loving wife, huh?
잠깐, 너 털사 못가!
Wait a minute.
Wait, you can't go to Tulsa.
잊었나 본데, 다음주에
제트팀 경기표 예매했잖아
Maybe you forgot, but we have tickets
to the Jets game next week!
미안하지만 난
못갈것 같아
I'm sorry, but I don't think
I'll be able to make it.
다른 팀도 아니고
제트 팀이란 말야!
But we were gonna go see the Jets!
넌 가면 안돼, 넌 우리를 하나로
묶어주는 접착제 같은 존재라구
You can't go. I mean, you're the glue
that holds this group together.
- 정말?
- 너 말구..
- Really?
- Not you.
다 괜찮을 거야
This whole thing is gonna be okay.
교외에 멋진 주택을 내준댔어
너희들도 놀러오면 좋잖아
They said they'd rent us a house in
the suburbs. You guys can come and visit.
꿈깨! 그런일은 절대로 없다
Oh, God, that is so not gonna happen.
너희들이 이사간다니
믿을수가 없어!
I can't believe you guys are moving.
- 이 아파트 내가 먼저 찜했다!
- 안돼!
- I call their apartment!
- No!
프렌즈 시즌 9
'소아과 의사'
- 여기 있어
- 고마워, 조이
- Here you go, Rach.
- Thank you, Joey.
그런데 카페인 마셔도
되는지 모르겠네
You know what?
I'm not even sure I can have caffeine.
벤 키울때 다 알아봤는데
커피 한잔은 젖먹이는데 지장없대
I went through this with Ben and Carol.
One coffee won't affect your milk.
그래? 확실히 해야지
위너 박사님한테 물어봐야겠어
Just to be sure,
I'm gonna call Dr. Wiener.
- 매번 낄낄 댈거니?
- 그럼
Every time?
별일도 아닌데 매번
의사한테 물어볼 필요없어
You don't have to call him
whenever you have a question, okay?
- 날 믿어, 내가 안다니까
- 알았어, 너 믿을게
- Trust me. I know this.
- All right. I trust you.
믿는다면서 전화는 왜걸어!
도대체 왜..
I can see you dialing.
I don't understand why..
쉿! 통화중이잖아!
위너 박사님?
I'm on the phone! Dr. Wiener?
로스와 레이첼이 애 키우는거 보니까
진짜 이상해, 꼭 어른들 같아
It's so weird seeing Ross and Rachel
with a baby. It's just so grownup.
그래, 우리 모두
어른이 되는것 같아
I know, yeah.
I feel like we're all growing up.
이름이 위너가 뭐냐?
웃겨 죽겠다!
A person named "Wiener."
God, that kills me.
- 봐, 너도 어른스럽잖아
- 그래, 사실은 말야
- Look at you all grownup.
- Well, actually, you know what?
나 정말 그런것 같아
I am, you know?
이번에 레이첼과의 일 겪으면서
깨달은 건데
Well, that whole thing
with Rachel made me realize..
나 좀더 진지한 관계를
시작할 준비가 된것 같아
that maybe I'm ready for a more
serious relationship, you know?
착하고, 성숙하고, 책임감 있는
여자를 만나고 싶어
Like, I'd like to meet a nice,
mature, commitment-minded lady.
외모는 그다지 중요하지 않아
And looks aren't as important as..
아냐, 예뻐야 해!
Nah, she's gotta be hot.
내가 아는사람 중에
그런사람 있을꺼야
You know, I might know somebody.
넌 나 남자 소개시켜줘
그래서 우리 더블 데이트 하자
How about you set me up
with someone, and we double-date?
그거 좋지
금요일 어때?
I can do that. Yeah.
How's Friday?
- 좋아!
- 좋아
- Done!
- All right.
- 정말 재밌겠다!
- 그래
Good, really?
Okay, let's see.
어디보자
All right.
아, 괜찮은 사람있다
샌디 푸팩
You know who's great?
Sandy Poopack.
"푸팩"?
"Poopack"?
좋아, 그럼 라나 팃와일러도
제껴야겠군
Yeah. All right.
Well, that rules out Lana Titwyler.
- 좋은 소식이 있어
- 털사 안가도 돼?
- I've got good news.
- You got out of the whole Tulsa thing?
그냥 소식이 있어
Okay, I have news.
자긴 털사에 안가도 돼
여기서 자기 일 계속해
You don't have to move to Tulsa.
You can stay here and keep your job.
어떻게 그렇게 됐어?
That's great! How?
상사랑 얘기해서 내가 일주일에
4일만 털사에 있기로 했어
My boss and I worked out a deal
where I'm in Tulsa four days a week.
그러니까 3일은 여기서
자기랑 지낼수 있어
So the other three,
I can be here with you.
자긴 일주일에 4일은
털사에 있어야 한다구?
So you're gonna be gone
four days a week?
싫어
No.
미안한데 싫다는 말
입에 붙어서 나온거 아냐?
I'm sorry, are you just
used to saying that?
아니, 자기랑 그렇게 오래
떨어져 있을수 없어
No. I can't be away
from you for that long.
- 정말?
- 자긴 내 남편인걸
- Really?
- Yeah, you're my husband.
1년에 208일을 자기와
다른 주에서 살긴 싫어
I won't live in a different state
than you for 208 days out of the year.
계산 한번 빠르다!
우리 털사지점에서 일할래?
That's fast math.
We could use you in Tulsa.
방법 알아봐준거 고마워
하지만 자기가 간다면 나도 갈거야
Thanks for trying to figure out a way,
but if you go to Tulsa, I go with you.
그런말 숨 안막히고
술술 잘하네!
You said that without gagging.
그러게!
I know!
어, 뭐라구요?
Well, excuse me?
그래요?
선생님도 소리질러요!
Oh, yeah?
Well, up yours too!
- 누군데 그래?
- 위너 박사님
- Who the hell was that?
- Dr. Wiener.
새벽 3시에 전화하는건
경우가 아니지
Rach, you can't call people
at 3:00 in the morning.
어쩜 박사님 부인이랑
똑같은 말을 하네!
You know what?
You sound just like his wife.
엠마한테 무슨
이상이라도 있어?
Was there anything
even wrong with Emma?
있으니까 이러지!
내가 미친 여자인줄 알아?
Yes, of course there is!
Okay? I'm not insane.
무슨 일인데?
What was it?
딸꾹질
Hiccups.
말했잖아, 별일 아닌걸로
자꾸 전화하지 말라구
I told you, you can't call him
every time any little thing comes up.
이젠 할수도 없어!
우리 엠마 다신 안봐주겠대
Well, not anymore I can't.
He fired us!
믿을수 있어?
Can you believe that?
박사님이 여기와서 육아 잡지로
네 머리를 때린다 해도 믿을수 있어
I could believe it if he came here and hit you
over the head with a copy of Highlights.
어떡하지?
소아과 의사 찾아봐야해
What are we gonna do?
We have to find a pediatrician.
잠깐, 모니카랑 자기 어렸을 때
Wait, Monica said that
when you guys were growing up..
봐준 선생님 좋다며?
이름이 뭐지?
you liked your doctor.
What was his name?
게틀먼 선생님?
Dr. Gettleman?
그건 별로 좋은 생각이
아닌것 같은데
Yeah, no, I don't think
that's a good idea.
그분 돌아가셨다고 들었어
In fact, I think he's dead.
난 왜 이렇게
되는일이 없지?
Why does everything happen to me?
레이첼, 내일 아침에
다른 의사 알아보자
I promise, first thing tomorrow,
we'll find another doctor.
내일 일찍 일어나야 하는데
나 몸이 별로 안좋아
But I gotta get up early,
and I'm not feeling well.
어디가? 안좋다니 무슨 소리야?
뭔데? 풍진 아냐?
You're not feeling well?
What do you have? Rubella?
엠마 곁에 가지마
예방주사 아직 안맞았어
Because don't go near Emma,
she has not had that shot.
그래, 잘 생각해보니까
꼭 풍진 같다!
You know, come to think of it,
it does feel rubella-like.
위너!
Wiener!
위너! 위너! 위너!
Wiener! Wiener! Wiener!
레이첼!
Rachel!
잘한다!
박사님이 난줄 알아버렸잖아!
Great! Now he's gonna
know it was me!
그리고 깐풍기요
And the kung pao chicken.
포크랑 접시 하나 주시고요
Utensils and plates for one.
제 주문 확인해 주시겠어요?
And can you read the order back to me?
맞아요
Great.
수고하세요
Yeah. Okay, thanks. Bye.
오늘 저녁 우리 더블데이트에
입을건데 어때?
So how is this
for our big double date tonight?
아이구, 이런!
Oh, my God.
그래?
내가 기대했던 반응 그대로네
Great. Just the reaction
I was hoping for.
나 소개해줄 여자 찾았어?
잊어버리지 않았나봐
Yeah, so you found someone for me?
You didn't forget?
물론이지
메리 앨런 마음에 들거야
Of course not.
And you'll love Mary Ellen.
아주 똑똑하고 귀엽고
재미있고..
She's really smart and cute
and funny and..
어떻게 아는진 말할수 없지만
3명이 자는 것에도 거부감이 없어
I can't tell you how I know this,
but she is not opposed to threesomes.
좋아
All right.
나 소개시켜줄 남자에
대해서도 얘기해봐
- So tell me something about my guy.
- No.
안돼
조금만 말해봐
이름이 뭐야?
Come on, give me something.
What's his name?
질문이 이해가 안가
I'm not sure I understand the question.
사람들이 그사람을
뭐라고 부르냐고
What do they call him?
- 마이크
- 마이크? 성은 뭔데?
- Mike.
- Mike. Okay, what's his last name?
젠장! 요즘은 로맨스에
비밀이라곤 없는거니?
Damn it! Is there no mystery left
in romance anymore?!
알았어, 마이크랑 이따가
식당에서 보자
We'll see you and Mike
at the restaurant in a couple hours.
- 그래, 알았어, 잘가
- 안녕, 그래
All right, great.
See you. Bye-bye.
왜 마이크라고 했지? 아는 사람중에
마이크는 없는데 왜 하필이면..
Why'd I have to say Mike? I don't know
a Mike! Why couldn't I have said..?
여긴 남자이름이 없잖아!
There's no guys in there!
애를 키우는게 이런 거구나?
So this is being a parent, huh?
잘할수 있을것 같다, 그지?
I think I can handle this.
퇴각, 퇴각
Too intense. Too intense.
드디어 얘기했어
Well, I did it.
털사로 간다고
레스토랑 직원들한테 얘기했어
I told my crew at the restaurant
I'm heading off to Tulsa.
- 그래? 다들 잘 받아드렸어?
- 응, 다행이도
- Oh, yeah? How'd they take it.
- Pretty well. Yeah.
훌륭한 부하들이었는데
They were brave little soldiers.
우는모습 안보이려고
노력하더라
Did their best to be stoic.
어떤 애들은 슬픔을 감추려고
하이파이브를 하더라고
Some of them even high-fived each other
to mask their pain.
좋은 의사 찾기가 하늘의 별따기야
내 무릎에 자기 몸 비벼댈
It's impossible to find a good doctor.
How do you know the good ones..
의사인지 아닌지 어떻게 구분한담
from the ones who'll push
their penis against your knee?
뭐라구?
Excuse me?
난 저게 무슨 말인지 알지
I know what she's talking about.
손놀림이 이상한
피아노 선생님도 알지?
You probably also had the piano teacher
with the wandering hands.
소아과 의사 새로 찾아봐야해
Well, we've gotta find
a new pediatrician.
로스가 밤부터 아파
엠마도 옮았을지 몰라
Ross was getting sick last night,
and Emma may have caught it.
- 게틀먼 선생님한테 가보지 그래?
- 로스가 돌아가셨다던데?
- Why don't you see Dr. Gettleman?
- Ross said he died.
아냐
지난주에도 그 딸 봤는걸?
He didn't die.
I just saw his daughter last week.
건강하시대, 그런데 걘
보톡스 주사가 실패했더라
She said he was fine.
Her, on the other hand, botched Botox.
잘됐다
엠마 데리고 가봐야지
Great. Well then, I'm gonna
take Emma to see him.
로스가 왜 그분
돌아가셨다고 했을까?
I wonder why Ross said that he died?
아마 어릴때 정신과 선생님이랑
헷갈렸나봐
Maybe he confused him
with his childhood therapist.
정신과 상담 받았어?
He saw a therapist?
밤마다 같은 악몽을 꿨거든
그것 때문에 고생좀 했지
He used to have a recurring nightmare.
It freaked him out.
무슨 꿈이었는데?
Wow, what was it?
내가 오빠 잡아먹는 꿈
That I was going to eat him.
마이크?
Mike!
네?
Yeah?
좋아요
Okay.
솔직히 내가 이런일에
끼어들다니 나답지 않네요
I can't believe
I'm doing this with you.
얼마전 9년간 사귄 여자랑 끝나서
Although I did just end
a nine-year relationship..
새로운 시도를 해야할 처지지만
so I should be open
to taking some risks.
좋았어, 그런 지루한
얘기는 지금해요
That's good.
Get all that boring stuff out now.
다 잘될거예요
나만 잘 따라와요
Everything is gonna be fine.
Follow my lead, okay?
마이크인 척만 하면 돼요
All you have to do is
pretend to be Mike.
- 난 마이크예요
- 그렇게 하면되요
- I am Mike.
- Attaboy.
저기 오네요
Here they come.
- 피비예요
- 마이크예요
- I'm Phoebe.
- Phoebe. Mike. How you doing?
- 반가워요
- 조이, 이쪽은 메리 엘런 젠킨스야
- Nice to meet you.
- Joey, this is Mary Ellen Jenkins.
마이크, 조이와는 어떻게
아는 사이예요?
So, Mike, how do you and Joey
know each other, anyway?
조이랑 어떻게 아냐구요?
How do Joey and I know each other?
그 질문 받을 때마다
한푼씩만 받았어도 부자됐을텐데
If I had a nickel for every time
somebody's asked me that.
- 학교 친구야
- 네, 대학친구죠
- From school.
- We met in college.
아니, 고등학교 친구
I mean high school.
와, 오래된 친구네요
요즘 하는일이 뭐예요?
You guys go way back, then.
So, what are you up to these days?
- 변호사예요
- 변호사 마이크!
- Well, I'm a lawyer.
- Mike, attorney at law!
- 그런데 때려치웠어요
- 뭐?
- Actually, I just gave up my practice.
- What?
넌 항상 그렇게
뒤통수치듯 소식을 전하는구나
That's the kind of thing
you usually run by me.
전부터 전문 피아니스트가
되고 싶었거든요
I want to play piano professionally.
If I don't do this now, I never will.
지금 아니면 못할것 같아서요
와, 대단해요
변호사보다 더 마음에 드네요
Great. I like that better
than the lawyer thing.
그럴까봐 이제서야
너한테 소개한 거야
Which is why I waited until now
to introduce you to Mike.
조이는 마이크가 지금도
변호사인줄 알았잖아요?
You thought he was still a lawyer.
아니, 그런뜻이 아녜요
칵테일 한잔 할래요?
No, that's not what I meant.
Let's get you a cocktail.
뭐해?
What are you doing?
털사에 있는 식당중에
자기 일자리 알아보는 거야
Looking for restaurant jobs
for you in Tulsa.
고마워라
뭐좀 있어?
That's so sweet.
Did you find anything?
- 찌꺼기 뿐이야
- 별볼일 없구나?
- Slim Pickins.
- Nothing, huh?
아니, '찌꺼기'가
바비큐 집 이름이야
No. Slim Pickins.
It's a barbecue joint.
요리사 구한대
사실 정식 요리사는 아닌것 같고
They're looking for a cook. Actually,
"cook" may be a bit of a stretch.
콩 삽질할 사람이
필요하대
They're looking for somebody
to shovel mesquite.
'찌꺼기'라니
이름 참 싸구려다
"Slim Pickins"? That is so cheesy.
참, '싸구려'에서도
사람 구한대
Well, So Cheesy also has an opening.
됐어
낸시라는 여자가 있는데
Honey, that's okay.
I know this woman, Nancy..
식당업계 헤드헌터야
정보가 좀 있을거야
who's a restaurant biz headhunter.
She may know something.
같이 가줘서
얼마나 고마운지 몰라
Can I say how much I appreciate
you coming with me?
털사에 가면 '찌꺼기'에서
근사하게 한턱 쏠게
When we get to Tulsa, I am taking you
for a great dinner at Slim Pickins.
'싸구려'?
So Cheesy?
'통돼지'?
Whole Hog?
털사에서 제대로된
밥 먹기 힘들겠군
It's gonna be tough
to keep kosher in Tulsa.
낸시?
모니카 겔러예요
Hi, Nancy?
Hi, it's Monica Geller.
잘 지내요
털사에 일자리 좀 알아보려구요
I'm good. Listen, I'm looking
for a job in Tulsa.
남편이 그쪽으로
전근가게 됐어요
Yeah, well, my husband's
been relocated.
남편을 사랑하니까요!
Because I love him.
아뇨, 뉴욕일은 싫어요
No, I don't want a job in New York.
'자부'에서 사람 구해요?
어머나!
Javu's looking? Oh, my God!
절 소개해 달라고 했다구요?
세상에!
He asked for me personally?
Oh, my God!
와, 정말 기분 좋네요
Wow, this is really,
really flattering.
하지만 털사로 이사가는데..
But I'm moving to Tulsa.
네, 그러니까 '자부'쪽에
전해주세요
So, just, if you would tell Javu..
그일 하겠다구요!
I'll take it!
안녕하세요? 레이첼 그린이에요
엠마 진료 예약했는데요
My name's Rachel Greene.
I have an appointment for Emma.
게틀먼 선생님 진료중이신데
곧 나오실 거예요
Dr. Gettleman is finishing up
with a patient. He'll be out shortly.
감기인것 같다
연쇄구균감염은 분명히 아냐
I think you just have a cold.
It's definitely not strep.
고맙습니다
Thanks, doctor.
- 막대사탕 줄까?
- 물어보시나 마나죠!
- Would you like a lollipop?
- Do you even have to ask?
살아계시더라구!
He is alive!
조이와 안지 오래됐다는데
It's so surprising that you and Joey
have known each other for so long..
한번도 얘기 못들었어요
and I've never heard about you.
실은 우리 한동안
사이가 안좋았어
That's because we had
a bit of a falling out.
마이크가 차로 우리 엄마를
치었거든
Mike hit my mom with a car.
- 그런적 없어!
- 괜찮아, 난 다 용서했어
- No, I didn't.
- That's okay. I have forgiven you.
우린 다시 친구고
이젠 다 괜찮아
Now we're friends again,
and everything's great.
어머님은 괜찮으세요?
Well, wait. Is your mom okay?
우리 지금 얘기중이잖아요
Please, we're trying
to have a conversation.
우리 인생의 나날들에서보다
훨씬 더 친절하네요
You're a lot nicer
on Days of Our Lives.
우리 인생의 나날들!
그래서 낯이 익었군!
Days of Our Lives!
That's why you look so familiar!
- 뭐라구요?
- 네?
- What?
뭐라구?
What?
둘이 모르는 사이야?
Do you not know each other?
물론 알지! 지금 마이크는
고등학교때 하던 놀이를 하는거야
Of course we do. He's playing a game
we used to play in high school.
서로 모르는척 하곤 했지
별별 장난을 다 쳤다니까
We pretend we don't know each other.
We played all kinds of games.
내가 너 칠칠치 못하다고
얼굴에 한방 먹였던거 기억나?
You remember that one where I punch
you in the face for not being cool?
마이크, 대답해봐요
조이 여자형제가 몇이죠?
Let me ask you something:
How many sisters does Joey have?
- 6명
- 무슨 소리야? 7이에요
- Six.
- No, he doesn't. He has seven.
뭐하는 거예요?
내가 7이라고 했는데
What are you doing? I said seven!
왜 모르는 사람을
소개한거야?
Joey, why did you set me up
with a stranger?
왜냐하면.. 더블 데이트 약속
까먹었거든, 미안해
Because I forgot about our date.
I'm so sorry.
나도 사과하죠, 분명히 말하지만
조이 어머님 친적 없어요
I'm sorry too. And just to be clear,
I didn't hit his mother with a car.
마음 같아선
지금 차에 치이고 싶군요
Although I'd like to be
hit by one right now.
그래요? 나가실까요?
Yeah, no problem.
난 오늘 데이트 위해 얼마나
애썼는데 어떻게 이럴수 있어?
You are unbelievable. I spent so much
time finding the perfect girl for you.
메리는 정말 똑똑하고
귀엽고 헤프단 말야!
Mary Ellen is really smart
and cute and loose.
틀린말 아니잖아!
Who are you kidding?
그런데 넌 길거리에서
아무나 끌어다 붙여?
You find some guy
off the street for me?
이건 모욕이야!
God, this is humiliating!
피비, 정말 미안해
마음에 안들면 다른 남자 찾아줄게
I'm so sorry. If you don't like this guy,
I can find you a better one.
마이크? 마이크!
Mike? Mike?
나 갈래
I'm out of here.
반가웠어요
It was nice meeting you.
- 당신도 가게요?
- 내 이름 말해봐요, 그럼 남죠
- You're leaving too?
- I'll stay if you can tell me my name.
잘가요
Have a good night.
내일 떠나는데
아직 짐 쌀거 많잖아?
We leave tomorrow,
and you still have a lot to pack.
맞아
You're right.
나 못갈것 같아
Maybe I shouldn't go.
뭐?
What?
낸시가 '자부'라고 아주
근사한 식당에 자리가 났대
So Nancy told me about this job
at this great restaurant, Javu?
그런데 털사에서 좀 멀어
But it's just
a little outside of Tulsa.
얼마나 먼데?
Well, how far outside?
맨해튼이래
Manhattan?
그일 하려구?
And you're thinking of taking it?
전엔 일보다 내가
더 중요하다더니
Before, you said that being with me
was more important than any job.
우선순위가 이렇게 되는군
옛날 일, 나, 새로운 일
But I guess now it's
old job, me, new job.
이 손 너무나 그리울 거야!
I'm gonna miss this hand!
무리한 요구라는거 알아
I know this is a lot to ask..
하지만 이건 엄청난 기회야!
but, my God, this is
a once-in-a-lifetime opportunity.
일주일에 나없이 4일이나
살순 없다며?
What happened to "you can't live
without me four days a week"?
잘 생각해보면 4일이
그렇게 긴것만은 아냐
Well, if you really think about it,
I mean, four days is not that long.
월요일엔 자기 출근전에 보고
I see you Monday
before you go to work..
목요일엔 퇴근하면 보고
and Thursday when you get back..
화요일엔 내가 늘 늦게 퇴근하니까
결국.. 제대로 못보는건
and I always work late on Tuesdays,
so really if you think about it..
수요일 하루뿐이야
it's really just one day.
하루 못보는것도 감당 못한다면
우리 진짜 문제 있는거야
And well, if we can't make it one day,
we got real problems, my friend.
- 그일 맡아
- 정말?
- I think you should take the job.
- Really?
자기가 원숭이처럼 꽥꽥될땐
그만큼 중요한 일인 거잖아
I know it must be important to you
when you start chattering like a monkey.
내가 들어본 말중
가장 고마운 얘기야
That's the nicest thing
anybody's ever said to me.
그렇게 원하던 일인데
포기하게 할순 없지
It's your dream job.
I can't make you pass it up.
자기가 너무 자랑스러워
Besides, I'm proud of you.
- 정말?
- 그래
- You are?
- Yeah.
털사 사람들이
부인은 어딨냐고 물으면
And when I get to Tulsa and
people say, "Where's the missus"..
'자부'의 요리사라고 말할거야
I'll tell them she's a chef at Javu.
날 멍하게 쳐다보면
And then, when they stare
at me blankly..
무례한 털사 농담을 늘어놓고
소외된 삶을 살아갈게
I'll make some offensive Tulsa joke,
and thus, begin my isolation.
- 소아과 의사 어땠어?
- 아주 마음에 들었어
- How was the pediatrician?
- I really liked him.
정말 정말 좋더라
Yeah, yeah.
It was really, really, really good.
- 아무말 안한다고 약속했지?
- 그래
- You promised not to say anything.
- I know.
로스가 아직도
자기 소아과 의사한테 진찰 받아!
Ross still sees his pediatrician!
미안
I don't care.
정말이야? 아직도
게틀먼 선생님한테 다녀?
Are you serious?
You still see Dr. Gettleman?
그분은 훌륭한 진단전문의야!
He is a brilliant diagnostician!
진단전문의?
'아야'전문의가 아니구?
Diagnostician or boo-boo fixer?
농담 아냐, 자신한테
맞는 의사한테 가봐
Seriously, you gotta go
to an appropriate doctor.
치열 교정 의사도 아니고
And not an orthodontist..
산부인과 의사도 아니고
not a gynecologist..
수의사도 아니라고
and not a veterinarian..
왜? 좀 우습긴 하지만
그분은 훌륭한 의사야
Why? I know it's a little weird,
but he is a great doctor, okay?
내 병력도 다 알고
He knows my medical history.
갈때마다 성의껏 봐주신다구
And every time I go in there,
he makes a big deal.
"이게 누구야! 내가 제일
좋아하는 환자군"
You know,
"Look, it's my favorite patient."
엉덩이에 체온기 꽂기
직전에 그러지 않던?
Does he say that before he sticks
his thermometer in your tushy?
대학 올때 어릴때 쓰던
담요 가지고 온게 누군데?
I seem to remember someone bringing
his security blanket to college.
그건 담요가 아냐!
벽걸이였다구
That was not a security blanket.
That was a wall hanging.
벽에 붙어있는 꼴을 못봤다!
It didn't spend much time on the wall!
어, 잠깐만요
Excuse me.
한번 만나고 싶었어요
시간 있어요?
Hi. I was hoping to run into you.
Can we talk?
좋아요
Sure.
소개해주고 싶은 사람이 있어요
Yeah. There's someone
I want you to meet.
이쪽은 고등학교때
가장 친한 친구예요
This is my best friend from high school.
죄송한데, 전 당신 모르는데요
I'm sorry, I don't think I know you.
봐요, 이렇게 말하기가
그렇게 어렵던가요?
How hard was that?
정말 미안해요
고개를 못들겠군요
Look, I'm sorry, really.
I'm so embarrassed.
앉아요
Please.
하지만 나, 정말 괜찮은 남자예요
내 보호관찰관한테 물어봐요
Really, I'm a pretty nice guy.
Just ask my parole officer.
재치있는 남자는 아니죠?
Apparently, I'm not a funny guy.
대체 왜 그랬죠?
Well, why did you go along with that?
저녁 공짜로 먹여준대서요
결과는 그렇지 못했지만
Because I was told that I'd get
a free dinner, which I didn't.
또 예쁜 여자 소개시켜준대서요
그건 사실이었어요
And that I'd meet a pretty girl,
which I did.
맞아요
That's true.
자신에 대해 말한것 중에
사실인게 있나요?
Well, is anything you told me
about yourself true?
내 진짜 이름은 마이크고
정말로 피아노를 쳐요
My name is Mike.
And I do play piano.
- 증명해봐요
- 여기 피아노가 없어서요
- Prove it.
- There isn't a piano here.
진짜 피아니스트라면
그건 핑계일 뿐이죠
That wouldn't stand in the way
of a true pianist.
알았어요
Okay.
정말 잘하는군요!
You are really good.
- 난 기타를 좀 쳐요
- 정말요? 멋지군요
- I play a little guitar myself.
- Really? That's great.
- 어떤 음악해요?
- 통기타로 포크송 같은 걸 하죠
- What kind of music do you play?
- Like acoustic, folksy stuff, you know?
지금은 '아이언 메이든' 계열
음악을 하고 있구요
But right now I'm working on
a couple lron Maiden covers.
언제 제가 한번..
Do you think that, maybe,
sometime, I could..
좋아요
어서 데이트 신청해요
It's okay. Go ahead, ask me out.
그러죠, 언제 나랑
데이트 할래요?
Okay. You think, maybe,
sometime I could take you out?
이런, 허를 찔렸네!
You just caught me off guard.
좋아요, 그러죠
Yeah, that would be nice.
좋다! 제일 친한
친구 둘이 사귀다니!
Look at this! My two best friends!
실례합니다
바보같은 소리지만
Excuse me.
I don't mean to be a jerk..
발진이 생긴 아기가
내뒤에 따라 들어왔어요
but the baby with the rash
came in after me.
선생님께서 곧 봐주실겁니다
- The doctor will be right with you, sir.
- I hear you..
그런데, 좀더 어려운
퍼즐은 없나요?
but do you have any harder puzzles?
엄마, '월리' 못찾겠어
Mommy, I can't find Waldo.
몇쪽 보고 있니?
What page are you on?
서커스에 간거 말야?
코끼리 뒤에 있어
What, the circus?
He's behind the elephant.
와, 댁의 아이도 '월리'를
무척 좋아하나봐요?
Wow. So your child's a big fan
of the Waldo books too?
네, 그래서 잘 알죠
Yeah, that's how I know.
- 로스라고 합니다
- 샐리예요
- I'm Ross, by the way.
- Hi, I'm Sally.
반지 안낀걸 보니 독신으로
애 키우시나봐요?
So no ring. Can I assume
you're also a single parent?
- 네, 맞습니다
- 정말 힘들죠?
- I am a single parent.
- It's hard, isn't it?
사회생활 할 틈이 없어요
어디서 사람들을 만나세요?
There's no time for a social life.
Where are you gonna meet someone?
- 글쎄요..
- 엄마, 못 찾겠..
- Well..
- Mommy, I can't..
해변 페이지? 보트를 봐
Sea shore? Row boat.
글쎄요, 전 새로운 사람들을..
소아과 병원에서 만나곤 하죠
Let's say, I don't know, you met
someone in the pediatrician's office.
귀여운 로스?
안으로 들어갈까?
Rossie? We're ready for you.
어, 네
Yeah..
가자, 로스 2세
들어가야지?
Come on, Ross Jr.
It's time to go in.
엄마?
Mommy.
엄마? 저 아저씨 왜저래?
Mommy, what's wrong with that man?
내가 월리 찾는거
도와줬잖니!
Hey, I helped you find Waldo!
- 다행이다! 아직 출발 안했구나
- 어디 있었어?
- Good, you haven't left yet.
- Where have you been?
게틀먼 선생님 병원에서
좀 오래 걸렸어
I got held up
at Dr. Gettleman's office.
어떤 이상한 사람 때문에
소동이 있었거든
There was some guy
that freaked everybody out.
다시 가면 안될거 같아
I don't think I'm going back there.
늦기전에 와서 다행이야
이젠 정말 가야겠다
You got here just in time.
I really have to go, buddy.
오, 챈들러
Oh, man.
- 도착하면 바로 전화해
- 전화할게, 사랑해
- Promise to call me when you land?
- Of course I will. I love you.
나도 사랑해
I love you too.
어허! 적당히 해라!
저기 미성년자 있는거 안보여?
Watch the tongue, people.
We got a baby over here.
- 잘가, 챈들러
- 잘있어
- Bye, Chandler.
- Bye.
- 잘가
- 안녕
- Bye, honey.
- Bye.
- 너 왜그래?
- 화나서 그런다
- What's the matter, Joe?
- I'm mad at you for leaving.
여기 떠나서
잘먹고 잘살아라!
You know, you're nothing
but a big leaver.
바보같은 가방 끌고
어디 잘 가보라구
A big leaver with a stupid suitcase.
싸우면 이별하는게
좀 쉬울까봐 이러는 거야?
Any chance you're trying to pick
a fight to make all of this easier?
짜식, 넌 역시 날 잘알아
Dude, you see right through me!
그럼.. 잘있어, 모니카
Okay, well.. Bye, Mon.
너희도 잘있어
Bye, Ross. Rachel.
- 엠마도 안녕
- 그래, 얼른가!
- Bye, Emma.
- Okay, bye-bye.
그래, 잘가라!
세상에..
Have a good trip. Okay.
Oh, my God.
챈들러!
잠깐만
Wait.
나한텐 옛날 일
It goes old job..
새로운 일
new job..
그리고 자기야
and you.
해야할 일이라
그런것 뿐이야
This is just something I have to do.
알아
I know.
많이 많이 사랑해
I love you so much.
그것도 알아
I know that too.
걱정마
곧 돌아간대두
Don't worry.
I'll be back before you know it.
그래, 달라지는건 없을거야
Yes, it will be the same.
그게 사실이니까 그렇지
Because I know, that's how.
약속할게
I promise.
진짜 진짜 약속해?
You double promise?
도착하면 연락해
Call me when you land.
- 나좀 바꿔줄래
- 그래, 안녕
- Can I talk now?
- Okay, bye.
- 조이!
- 비행기 타야 한대
- Joey!
- He had to board.